Guide to the Larry Mitchell papers, 1954-2005.
Mitchell, Larry Papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Larry Mitchell papers, 1954-2005.
7820
Mitchell, Larry.
Approximately 6 cubic feet.
Diaries, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mitchell's publications, drafts of his and other people's writings (including a draft of a Harvey Fierstein piece), interviews, reviews and awards for his writing and the work of Calamus Books, and personal and family papers, including journals and diaries.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
American author and publisher, born in Muncie, Indiana in 1938. Mitchell was the founder of Calamus Books, an early small press devoted to gay male literature, and a cofounder of Gay Presses of New York in 1981. Mitchell also wrote fiction dealing with the gay male experience in New York City during the 1970s and 1980s, including the book of short stories My life as a mole (1989) and the novel The terminal bar (1982). The feature film Acid snow (1998) is based on Mitchell's novel of the same name. He died in Ithaca, New York in 2012.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Mitchell's publications, drafts of his and other people's writings (including a draft of a Harvey Fierstein piece), video recording of Marsha P. Johnson, an African American drag queen who was a prominent participant in the 1969 Stonewall uprising in New York City and was an outspoken advocate for gay rights. Also includes interviews, reviews and awards for his writing (including the Lambda Literary Award) and the work of Calamus Books, as well as personal and family papers, including journals and diaries and a copy of Mitchell's baby book.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Mitchell, Larry.; Mitchell, Larry.; Johnson, Marsha.
Subjects:
Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Gays' writings, American.; Gay men -- New York (State) -- New York
Form and Genre Terms:
Manuscripts for publication.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Due to the fragility and potential degradation of moving image and sound recordings, viewing and listening is limited to items that have been digitized. If an item is in another media format, you may request to have the item digitized for access. Information on ordering access copies may be found on our Reproductions and Permissions page.
CONTAINER LIST
- Diary Entry, March 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Liberace Signed Program, October 22, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Literary Lapses - Student Compositions from the High School of Burris Lab School at Ball State Teachers College, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Burris High School 25th Reunion (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Burris High School Junior Plays Program (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Burris High School Diploma and Commencement Program, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Burris High School Yearbook, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Burris High School Notebooks (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Burris High School Report Cards (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Beta Chi of Colby College (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Colby College Diploma and Commencement Program, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Colby College Yearbook, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Colby 2000 Certificate (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Columbia Dissertation: "Failure and Success - The American Theatre and its Playwrights" (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Columbia Transcripts (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Thoughts on Dostoyevsky" by Larry Mitchell (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Why Straight Men Hate Queer Men" and "All Those Years Wasted Sliiping [sic] With the Wrong Men" (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Journal with Extra Notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Acid Snow Publicity (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Acid Snow Reviews (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Acid Snow Production Packet and Offering Document (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Acid Snow Screenplay First Draft, November 12, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Acid Snow Screenplay First Draft Large Font, November 12, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Acid Snow Screenplay Second Draft Reading, April 15, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Acid Snow Screenplay Second Draft, December 20, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Acid Snow Screenplay Final Draft, June 5, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Acid Snow Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Gaze Magazine - Interview with Larry Mitchell and Joel Itman, December 27, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- ISBN Logs (Box 1, Folder 29)
- "Single People" - Story by Larry Mitchell, July 1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Lambda Awards and Book Report (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Gay Press Miscellany: Clippings, Correspondence, Photos, etc. (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
- Queer Associated Press (Box 1, Folder 34)
- My Life as a Mole Posters - Reading by Neal Wach (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "The Story of Orchard" by Eugene Salandra - Adapted from Larry Mitchell, September 6, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Eugene Salandra Correspondence, September 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Pink Satin Bombers - "An Evening of Faggot Theatre", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
- Pink Satin Bombers - Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Get It While You Can" - Play by Larry Mitchell (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Get It While You Can" - Draft and Revisions (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- "Get It While You Can" - Theater for the New City (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Personal Correspondence - Ron Schreiber and others (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Personal Correspondence - Dorotha and Ray Mitchel (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Garden of Memory Funeral Home (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dorotha Mitchell Death Record (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Letters to Dorotha Mitchell from Cecil (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Baby Books and Birth Certificates (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Ray Mitchell Diploma (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Ray Mitchell Diploma (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Family Genealogy (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Misc. Legal Papers (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
- Passports, Bank Book, Health Insurance Card, Faculty ID Card (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Final Grades, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Class Notes, February 1974-April 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Course Outlines and Sociology of Men Transcripts (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Scrapbook Contents (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Cat Drawing and Weave Wallet (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Gaycon and Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Jokes (Box 2, Folder 24)
- "Going to Camp: A Meditation About Aids, Quarantine, Exile, and Personal Loss" Art Book (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Homohomo Phobia - Notes With Mike, October 11, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Programs: NY Gay Film Festival (1990), Double Edge: Edmund Nieman and Nurit Tilles, Duo-Pianists (Box 2, Folder 27)
- "Clara the Pigeon with Cement Shoes" - By Larry Mitchell, Illustrated by Frances Lyshak (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
- "Cold Shoulder" - Second Draft (Box 2, Folder 31)
- "Freaky Pussy" - Play by Harvey Fierstein Manuscript and Letter, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Four Partial Manuscripts (Box 2, Folder 33)
- "Art Books," "Bad Parties" (Box 2, Folder 34)
- "Sex Histories" - Boyd McDonald Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Calamus Books Business Mail (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Unidentified Play Manuscript, Pages 18-195 (Pages 1-17 missing) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Unidentified Play Manuscript, Pages 196-361 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Unidentified Play Manuscript, Pages 362-437 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Unidentified Play Manuscript, Misc. Unnumbered Pages and Papers (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Unidentified Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Unidentified Play Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Unidentified Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Unidentified Art History Manuscript, September 14, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Unlabeled Play (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "Dad is Dead" - Story (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Three Plays by Robert Patrick: "Michelangelo's Models," "Angel, Honey, Baby, Darling, Dear," "Orpheus and Amerika", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- "Tulips and Cadavers" - by Jimmy Camicia, Theater for the New City (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "Three Small Men" - A Play in One Act by Jimmy Camicia (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Misc. Jimmy Camicia Plays (Box 3, Folder 15)
- "The Disappeared" (Box 3, Folder 16)
- "The Parade" - by Frank McLaughlin, Manuscript and Letter to Larry Mitchell (Box 3, Folder 17)
- "Liberation and Trauma at Terminal Bar," Interviews with Brad Ellis, John Lurie, Lavinia Co-Op, Evan Lurie, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- "Sin: A Virtue" - by Lawrence Goldman, Manuscript and Letter (Box 3, Folder 19)
- "Soundzimpossible" - by Ulla, Manuscript and Letter, May 13, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- "Consenting Adulterers" - by Valdeen (Box 3, Folder 21)
- "The Brain Eaters" - by Gary Indiana (Missing Last Pages), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Misc. Gary Indiana Plays (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
- "Poems from Before I Shaved My Mustache" - by Elmer L. Kline (Box 3, Folder 25)
- "Night Sweat" - Play by Robert Chesley (Box 3, Folder 26)
- "Night Sweat" Reviews (Box 3, Folder 27)
- "Like A Christmas Tree" - Play by Etel Adnan (Box 3, Folder 28)
- "Dominion" by Emme Edmunds (Box 3, Folder 29)
- "Filth: An S.T.H. Chap-book" (Box 3, Folder 30-32)
- "The Secret" - Written and Illustrated by Francie Lyshak (Box 3, Folder 33)
- "Public Haiku" (Box 3, Folder 34)
- "Marginality" - by Edgar Z. Friedenberg (Box 3, Folder 35)
- "Cruising the Movies" - by Boyd McDonald (Box 3, Folder 36)
- "Blue is for Boys" - Robert Patrick (Box 3, Folder 37)
- "Looking for a New Last Name" (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Steven J. Powsner Query Letter and First Chapter (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Photographs
  - Scrapbook Photos, 1930s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Photos (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Family Photos (Box 4)
  - Gatlinburg, October 1982 (Box 4)
  - Apt 1-101 (Box 4)
  - Bardstown - Dinner, Train, Show, Etc., June 10-14, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Dorotha Mitchell (Box 4)
  - Pontotoc (Box 4)
  - Bridge Parties (Box 4)
  - Ray Mitchell and Family (Box 4)
  - Gulf Shores (Box 4)
  - Cecil's Family (Box 4)
  - Nancy Lineback's Family (Box 4)
  - Pink Satin Bombers (Box 4)
  - Straight to Hell (Box 4)
  - Historic Family Photos, 1910s-1930s (Box 4)
  - Negatives, Cards, and Other Photos (Box 4)
- Notebooks
  - Diary, 1955 (Box 4)
  - "The Genealogy of a Dickey Family" by Homer B. Dickey (Box 4)
  - Address Book (Box 4)
  - Cape House Guest Books, 1976-1999 (Box 4)
  - Travel Journal (Box 4)
  - Journal, July 1975 (Box 4)
  - Unlabeled, undated Journals (Box 4)
  - III 118-232, August 2, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Sociology 220 Marriage and Family, 1983 (Box 4)
  - The Modern Family (Box 4)
  - January pp 1-135 (Box 4)
  - January: The Winter Book. pp 136-226 (Box 4)
  - January III: pp 227-317 (Box 4)
  - January IV: pp 318-457 (Box 4)
  - DD 1-50 (Box 4)
  - DD 51-89 (Box 4)
  - DD 90- (Box 4)
  - Revisions: Draft #2 (Box 4)
  - "The Disappeared" P. 71-90 (Box 4)
  - Practiced by Love, Horney for Love [sic] (Box 4)
- Other Items
  - Rolodex Containers (Box 4)
  - 1992 Lambda Literary Award, MU-1462 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook: Our Vacation: Japan, Hong Kong, San Francisco, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Photo Scrapbooks (Box 5)
  - Misc. Travel Scrapbooks (Box 5)
  - Oversized Papers (Box 6)
    Newspaper clippings, Acid Snow and other book proofs, oversized photographs, Dorotha Mitchell diploma
- Media
  - "Acid Snow" - Screenplay Safety Copy, FD-68 (Box 7)
  - Playtran.mac, FD-69 (Box 7)
  - "Unknown Singer" Magnetic Tape, tr-10645 (Box 7)
  - Unlabeled Magnetic Tape, tr-10646 (Box 7)
  - Larry Mitchell Interview, January 17, 2009, New York City, tr-10647 (Box 7)
  - Sociology of Men - Gabrielle Daniels, Spring 1983, tr-10648 (Box 7)
  - Bud (?) Message to 3 St, tr-10649 (Box 7)
  - Bill Rice / Beginning Rose, tr-10650 (Box 7)
  - Day After - Sass - All Ballads, tr-10651 (Box 7)
  - Duke Ellington Big Band / Mr. B, tr-10652 (Box 7)
  - Louie and Oscar Peterson, tr-10653 (Box 7)
  - Thelonius Solo, tr-10654 (Box 7)
  - Unlabeled Cassette Tape, tr-10655-tr-10656 (Box 7)
  - Unlabeled Message Cassettes, tr-10657-tr-10658 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: M. Resnik, November, 1965; tr-10659 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Duberman, December 30, 1965; tr-10660 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: R. Rebman, Reel #1, January 3, 1966; tr-10661 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: William Hanley, April 5, 1966; tr-10662 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Roger Herson, Reel #1, April 6, 1966; tr-10663 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Speigelglass, Reel #1, April 16, 1966; tr-10664 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Speigelglass, Reel #2, April 16, 1966; tr-10665 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Jim Herlichy, April 19, 1966; tr-10666 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Joe Margenstern, April 26, 1966; tr-10667 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Arthur Laurents, May 17, 1966; tr-10668 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Howard Teichman, May 25, 1966; tr-10669 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Frevoeli, June 6, 1966; tr-10670 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Dan Schary, June 8, 1966; tr-10671 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Joseph Kramer, Reel #2, June 22, 1966; tr-10672 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Jack Gelber, Reel #1, June 24, 1966; tr-10673 (Box 7)
  - Living Letters: Jack Gelber, Reel #2, June 24, 1966; tr-10674 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow", V-8932 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow" Promo, V-8933 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow" Cy's Loops, Reels 1-5A, V-8934 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow" Demo, V-8935 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow" (With Temp Tracks), V-8936 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow" Promo, V-8937 (Box 7)
  - "Acid Snow" Trailer, V-8938 (Box 7)
  - "Where Little Demons Dwell" by Alex Steyermark, V-8939 (Box 7)
  - Cape Cod - Bill, Larry, Eddie, 1992; V-8940 (Box 7)
  - "Undercurrent Incorporated" - Jim Neu, V-8941 (Box 7)
  - "Something Borc02 level="item"ed… Something New" by Joel Itman, V-8942 (Box 7)
  - Joel Itman Demo, V-8943 (Box 7)
  - "PSA," "Carmel," "Purple Grapes," "Something Borrowed," "Globo Night," "The Following" - Joel Itman, V-8944 (Box 7)
  - "Bloolips" by Michael Kasino, PAL Format [Due to fragility and potential degradation, please use the DVD copy of this video in same box - DVD-1496], V-8945 (Box 7)
  - "Marsha" [Due to fragility and potential degradation, please use the DVD copy of this video in same box - DVD-1497], V-8946 (Box 7)
  - "Bloolips" by Michael Kasino, Master Betacam [Due to fragility and potential degradation, please use the DVD copy of this video in same box - DVD-1496, V-8947 (Box 7)
  - "Bloolips" by Michael Kasino [Due to fragility and potential degradation, please use the DVD copy of this video in same box - DVD-1496, V-8948 (Box 7)
  - Richard George Murray Reading at Ulla Dydo's VHS-C, V-8949 (Box 7)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Publications and Books- cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
The Advocate
Arts Magazine
Extra!
HX: Homo Xtra
Inches
Lies of Our Times
Lavender Lifestyles
Next Magazine
NYQ
Out and About
Outweek
Paper Magazine
The Pink Paper
QW
Red
The Source
SPIN
Theater Week
The Times Book Review
Spy
Bumbalo, Victor Niagara Falls and Other Plays, 1984
Flannigan, Jim Don The Burp and Other Stories, 1980
Mitchell, Larry Acid Snow, 1993
Mitchell, Larry The Faggots and Their Friends Between Revolutions, 1977
Mitchell, Larry My Life As A Mole and Five Other Stories, 1988
Mitchell, Larry The Terminal Bar, 1982
Mitchell, Larry My Life As A Mole and Five Other Stories, 1988
Schreiber, Ron Tomorrow Will Really Be Sunday, 1984